What do you see?
这是什么？
Most of you see a barbershop,
大部分人看到的是理发店
but I see an opportunity:
我看到的却是机会
an opportunity for health,
促进健康的机会
an opportunity for health equity.
促进健康平权的机会。
For black men, the barbershop is not just a place
对黑人来说，理发店不仅仅是
where you get your hair cut or your beard trimmed.
一个帮你剪头发、刮胡子的地方。
No, it's much more than that.
不，远远不止如此。
Historically, the barbershop has been a safe haven for black men.
历史上， 理发店是黑人的避风港
It's a place where we go for friendship,
是我们获得友谊
solidarity and solace.
相互支持和安慰的地方
It's a place where we go to get away from the stress of the grind of work and sometimes home life.
是我们排解压力从繁重的工作和家庭压力解脱出来的地方。
It's a place where we don't have to worry about how we're being perceived by the outside world.
在这里我们不用担心外界眼光
It's a place where we don't feel threatened, or threatening.
在这里我们不会感到威胁和被他人威胁的地方。
It's a place of loyalty and trust.
一个充满忠诚和信任的地方。
For that reason,
因为这些原因
it's one of the few places where we can fearlessly be ourselves
它是少数几个我们可以毫无顾虑地做自己
and just ... talk.
轻松聊天的地方。
The talk, the shop talk, the conversation,
闲扯、乱聊、谈心
that is the essence of the black barbershop.
这就是黑人理发店的本质。
I can remember going to the barbershop with my dad as a kid.
我记得小时候和爸爸去理发店
We went to Mr. Mike's barbershop every other Saturday.
我们每隔一个周六去麦克先生家的理发店
And like clockwork, the same group of men would be there every time we went,
就像钟表发条一样，每次我们去都会有同样一群人在那里
either waiting on their favorite barber
要么在等他们最喜欢的理发师
or just soaking up the atmosphere.
要么沉浸在那种氛围中。
I can remember the jovial greeting that warmly welcomed us every time we went.
我记得每次去的时候都受到热情的问候。
"Hey Rev," they would say to my dad.
“嘿，小雷。” 他们向我爸打招呼。
He's a local pastor, and they treated him like a celebrity.
我爸是当地的牧师，他们像对待名人一样对待他。
"Hey young fella, how you doing?"
“嘿，小家伙，你好。”
they would say to me,
他们向我打招呼。
making me feel just as special.
这让我觉得自己很特别。
I remember the range of the conversations was immense.
我记得谈话的主题无所不包。
The men would talk about politics and sports and music
男人们会谈论政治、体育和音乐
and world news, national news,
国际新闻、国内新闻
neighborhood news.
邻居的新情况
There was some talk about women
有时也会谈论女人
and what it was like to be a black man in America.
以及身为黑人在美国是什么感觉。
But many times they also talked about health.
但很多时候他们还会谈论健康。
The conversations about health were lengthy and deep.
他们会长时间地深入讨论。
The men often recounted their doctor's recommendations
他们经常会详述医生的建议
to cut salt in their diet
减少对盐的摄入
or to eat less fried foods
少吃油炸食品
or to stop smoking
停止抽烟
or to reduce stress.
或者减少压力
They talked about the different ways you could reduce stress,
他们会谈论很多不同的减压方法
like simplifying one's love life --
比如简化爱情生活
(Laughter)
（笑）
all ways to treat high blood pressure.
还有治疗高血压的各种方式。
There's a lot of talk about high blood pressure in the barbershop.
在理发店有很多关于高血压的谈话
That's because almost 40 percent of black men have it.
因为接近40%的黑人都患有高血压。
That means that almost every single black man
这意味着几乎所有单身黑人男性
either has high blood pressure
要么患有高血压
or knows a black man who has it.
要么认识得高血压的人。
Sometimes, those conversations in the barbershop
有时候，这些在理发店的谈话
would be about what happens when high blood pressure is not adequately addressed.
是有关高血压没有得到充分治疗时造成的后果。
"Say, did you hear about Jimmy? He had a stroke."
“你听说杰米怎么了吗？他中风了。”
"Did you hear about Eddie? He died last week.
“你听说艾迪怎么了吗？他上周死了。
Massive heart attack.
严重心脏病
He was 50."
他才50岁。”
More black men die from high blood pressure than from anything else,
黑人死于高血压的人数远高于其他种族
even though decades of medical wisdom and science have demonstrated
哪怕几十年来，医疗和科技进步证明
that death from high blood pressure can be prevented with timely diagnosis and appropriate treatment.
只要及时诊断和正确治疗高血压引发的死亡是可以避免的。
So why is high blood pressure so differentially deadly for black men?
那为什么黑人死于高血压的人数如此之高？
Because too often, high blood pressure is either untreated or under-treated in black men,
因为很多患有高血压的黑人要么得不到治疗要么治疗不充分
in part because of our lower engagement with the primary healthcare system.
大多因为参加初级保健制度的黑人很少
Black men, in particular those with high blood pressure,
尤其是那些患高血压的黑人
are less likely to have a primary care doctor than other groups.
相对于其他群体更不大可能拥有一个保健医生。
But why?
为什么？
Some of our earliest research on black men's health
一些关于黑人健康的早期研究表明
revealed that for many, the doctor's office is associated with fear,
诊所对很多黑人来说意味着恐惧
mistrust,
猜疑
disrespect,
轻视
and unnecessary unpleasantness.
以及不必要的不愉快经历。
The doctor's office is only a place that you go when you don't feel well.
诊所是你不舒服时去的地方。
And when you do go, you might wait for hours
当你去了诊所你可能需要等待数个小时
only to get the run-around
只等来各种怠慢
and to be evaluated by a stoic figure in a white coat
然后穿白大褂的冰冷人士
who only has 10 minutes to give you
花十分钟来做检查
and who doesn't value the talk.
而且根本懒得和你谈话。
So it's no wonder that some men don't want to be bothered
难怪一些人不想这么麻烦
and skip going to the doctor altogether,
于是压根不去见医生
especially if they feel fine.
特别是他们感觉还行的时候。
But herein lies the problem.
但这里就会产生了问题。
You can feel just fine
虽然你感觉无恙
while high blood pressure ravages your most vital organs.
高血压却在你身体的大部分重要器官里肆虐。
This is Denny Moe,
这是丹尼摩 (Denny Moe)
owner of Denny Moe's Superstar Barbershop in Harlem.
纽约哈莱姆区丹尼摩超级巨星理发店店主。
I've been lucky enough to have Denny as my barber for the last eight years.
过去八年，有丹尼做我的理发师，我很幸运。
He said to me once,
他曾经跟我说
"Hey Doc, you know,
“医生，你知道吗
lots of black men trust their barbers more than they trust their doctors."
许多黑人宁可相信他们的理发师也不相信他们的医生。”
This was stunning to me, at first,
起初我很震惊
but not so much when you think about it.
但我仔细想了一下后就不惊讶了
Black men have been with their current barbers
黑人和他们的理发师认识的时间
on average as long as I've been with Denny, about eight years.
平均达到八年和我认识丹尼的时间一样长。
And black men see their barbers about every two weeks.
黑人每两星期见他们的理发师一次
Not only do you trust your barber with your look and with your style,
他们不仅在外貌和风格塑造上信任理发师
but you also trust him with your secrets and sometimes your life.
而且在分享秘密、有时在私人生活方面也信任理发师
Denny, like many barbers, is more than just an artist,
丹尼就像很多理发师，不仅仅是艺术家
a businessman and confidant.
商人、密友。
He's a leader and a passionate advocate for the well-being of his community.
他还是社区健康的领袖和热情的号召者。
The very first time I walked into Denny Moe's shop,
我第一次走进丹尼摩的理发店
he wasn't just cutting hair.
他不仅仅在为客人理发
He was also orchestrating a voter registration drive
他正激励顾客去注册，成为选民
to give a voice to his customers and his community.
为他的顾客和社区发声。
With this kind of activism, and community investment that typifies the black barbershop,
这种活动和社区投资是黑人理发店的典型做法
of course the barbershop is a perfect place
因此理发店理所当然是个完美的地方
to talk about high blood pressure and other health concerns in the community.
来讨论高血压和社区里的其他健康问题。
First, the barbershop is not a medical setting,
首先，理发店不是一个医疗机构
and so it doesn't have all the negative psychological baggage that comes along with that.
因此没有随之而来的负面心理负担。
When you're in a barbershop,
当你在理发店里时
you're in your territory, and you're among friends
你在你的领地里，在朋友中间
who share your history,
他们了解你的历史
your struggle and your health risks.
你的挣扎和你的健康风险。
Second, because the barbershop is a place of connection,
第二，因为理发店是一个关系网
loyalty and trust,
人们忠诚而彼此信任
it's a place where you're more open to have a conversation about health
所以你会在健康话题上敞开心扉
and especially about high blood pressure.
尤其是有关高血压的。
After all, conversations about high blood pressure
毕竟，有关高血压的交谈
have all the elements of great shop talk:
具备所有精彩的商店谈话的元素：
stress and high blood pressure,
压力和高血压
food and high blood pressure,
食物和高血压
relationships and high blood pressure,
人际关系和高血压
and yes, what it's like to be a black man in America and high blood pressure.
而且没错，美国黑人生存处境与高血压的关系。
But you can do more than just talk about high blood pressure
但除了在理发店里谈论高血压
in the barbershop.
你还可以做更多。
You can concretely take action.
你可以切实采取行动。
Here we have an opportunity to partner with the Denny Moe's of the world
我们有机会与丹尼摩的理发店合作
and empower communities to address the health inequities that uniquely affect it.
帮助社区更好地处理导致高血压的保健不公平现象。
When high blood pressure screening expanded from clinics and hospitals to communities in the 1960s and '70s,
1960和70年代当高血压筛查从诊所和医院扩展到社区
black physicians like Dr. Eli Saunders in Baltimore
黑人医师，比如巴尔的摩的爱丽桑德斯(Eli Saunders)博士
and Dr. Keith Ferdinand in New Orleans
新奥尔良的基斯费迪南德(Keith Ferdinand)博士
were at the forefront of bringing health promotion to community hubs in urban black neighborhoods.
率先在城市黑人社区的中心枢纽引入更好的保健措施。
These pioneers paved the way for my professional journey
这些先驱为我的职业生涯铺平道路
with barbershops and health, which began in Chicago in medical school.
我从芝加哥的医学院开始将理发店和健康联系在一起。
The very first research project that I worked on as a medical student
我作为医学院学生的第一个研究项目
was to help design healthcare interventions
是帮助设计保健干预措施
that would appeal to black men.
以便吸引黑人就医。
We conducted about a dozen focus groups
我们有大约12个焦点小组
with a broad cross-section of black men,
广泛囊括各个类型的黑人
and we learned that for them,
我们让他们了解到
being healthy was as much about being perceived as healthy
健康不仅仅是看上去健康
as it was about feeling healthy,
而且要感觉健康
and that feeling good went hand in hand with looking good.
而感觉健康也会让人看起来气色更好。
This work led to the development of Project Brotherhood,
这推动了兄弟项目(Project Brotherhood)的发展
a community clinic founded by Dr. Eric Whitaker
这是艾瑞克惠特克(Eric Whitaker)博士创办的一家社区诊所
that provided tailored healthcare to black men.
为黑人群体提供量身定做的医疗保健。
Part of this tailored care
部分特殊医疗包括
involved having a barber on the premises
将理发师纳入其中
to reward the men who came for needed healthcare with a free haircut,
为那些前来进行所需治疗的人提供一次免费理发作为奖励
to let the men know that we, too, valued how they looked as well as how they felt,
让他们知道我们就像重视他们的感受一样重视他们的外表
and that what was important to them was also important to us.
他们重视的东西也是我们重视的东西。
But while there's only one Project Brotherhood,
虽然兄弟项目只有一个
there are thousands of black barbershops
但我们还有数千家理发店
where the intersection of health and haircuts can be cultivated.
我们可以充分开发这些健康和理发的交汇点。
The next stop on my journey was Dallas, Texas,
我行程的下一站是德州的达拉斯
where we learned that barbers were not only willing
我们发现那里的理发师不仅仅愿意
but fully able to roll up their sleeves and participate
而且完全有能力卷起袖子
in delivering needed health services   to improve
参与到传播必要的医疗服务工作中来
the health of their customers and their community.
为促进顾客健康和提升社区做贡献。
We teamed up with an amazing cadre of black barbers
我们将很多杰出的黑人理发师组织起来
and taught them how to measure blood pressure
教会他们如何测量血压
and how to counsel their customers
怎样为顾客提建议
and refer them to doctors
向他们推荐医生
to help manage high blood pressure.
帮助他们控制血压。
The barbers were not only willing to do it
理发师们不仅愿意这么做
but they were damn good at it.
而且他们做得太棒了。
Over a three-year period,
在三年中
the barbers measured thousands of blood pressures
理发师们为数千人测量了血压
resulting in hundreds of black men being referred to doctors
介绍数百名黑人前往就医
for medical care of their high blood pressure.
接受高血压的治疗。
These barber-doctor partnerships
这些理发师和医生的合作项目
resulted in a 20 percent increase in the number of men who were able to achieve target blood pressure levels
导致能够达到目标血压水平的人 提高了20%
and a three-point drop, on average, in the blood pressure of each participant.
每个参与者的血压指数平均降低了三点。
If we were to extrapolate that three point drop to every single black man with high blood pressure in America,
如果我们能让每一个患高血压的美国黑人的血压指数都降低三点
we would prevent 800 heart attacks, 500 strokes and 900 deaths
我们就能在一年时间内防止由高血压引起的
from high blood pressure in just one year.
800次心脏病、500次中风和900例死亡。
And our experience with barbershops has been no different in New York City,
我们与纽约理发师的合作也一样
where my journey has currently led me.
这也是我目前开展工作的地方。
With an incredible team of diverse research assistants,
我的队伍很出色
community health workers and volunteers,
我们有多元化的研究助手社区保健工人和志愿者
we've been able to partner with over 200 barbershops
我们已经与超过200家理发店
and other trusted community venues
以及其他可信的社区场所合作
to reach over 7,000 older black men.
接触到超过7000名黑人。
And we've offered high blood pressure screening and counseling to each and every one of them.
我们为每个人提供高血压筛查和咨询。
Thanks to Denny Moe
谢谢丹尼摩等众多理发师
and the myriad other barbers  and community leaders
以及社区领导们
who shared the vision of opportunity and empowerment to make a difference in their communities,
他们也看到了改变社区的机遇和力量。
we've been able to not only lower blood pressure in our participants,
我们不仅降低了项目参与者的血压
but we've also been able to impact other health indicators.
而且还影响到其他健康指数。
So what do you see?
所以，你怎么看？
What is your barbershop?
你的“理发店”是什么？
Where is that place for you
你心目中的这个地方是哪里？
where people who are affected by a unique problem can meet a unique solution?
那个能够为面对独特难题的人们提供独特的解决方式的地方？
When you find that place, see the opportunity.
当你找到那个地方，那就是你的机会。
Thank you.
谢谢。
(Applause)
（掌声）